Now, here's where the word naive comes in Naive Bayes.
现在我们将了解朴素贝叶斯中的朴素一词的含义
We're going to make a pretty naive assumption here.
我们将做出一个非常朴素的假设
Let's look at the probability of two events happening together,
我们看看两个事件同时发生的概率
so P of A and B.
P(A &amp; B)
We can also read this a P of A intersection B.
还可以写成 P(A ∩ B)
And we're going to say that this is the product of P of A and P of B.
等于 P(A) 和 P(B) 的积
Now, this only happens when the two events are independent.
只有这两个事件相互独立时才会发生
If they're not, then this is not true.
如果不相互独立 则不成立
For example, if A is the event of it being hot
例如 如果 A 是外面很热的概率
outside and B is the event of it being cold outside,
B 是外面很冷的概率
then they both have a positive probability.
它们的概率都为正
But now, what's the probability of both events happening at the same time?
两个事件同时发生的概率是多少？
This will be zero, since it can't be hot and cold at the same time.
将为 0 因为不可能同时很热又很冷
So, this formula doesn't follow because the events of
这个公式不成立
being hot and being cold are dependent on each other.
因为很冷和很热是相互依赖的
But in a Naive Bayes, we will assume that our probabilities are independent.
但是在朴素贝叶斯定理中 我们假设概率是相互独立的
This, as we said, is a false and naive assumption,
这种假设是天真、不成立的假设
but in practice, it works very well and it makes our algorithm very fast.
但在实践中效果很好 使算法速度很快
Another formula I will use is a formula for conditional probability.
我将使用的另一个公式是条件概率公式
These are two ways of writing P of A intersection B.
这是 A 交 B 的概率的两种写法
And this is the basis for our base theorem.
这是贝叶斯定理的基础
But the trick we'll use here is to forget about P of B.
采用的技巧是忘记 P(B)
And now, we don't have these being equal.
现在不是等于
But we have P of A given B to be proportional to P of B given A times P of A.
而是变成 P(A | B) 与 P(B | A)P(A) 成比例
This will work very well because in the practice,
效果很好 因为在计算时
P of B will cancel out,
P(B) 将被消除
so the fact that these two are proportional is very useful.
因此这两个成比例很重要
And now, here's what we want.
现在我们要解决的问题是
We have an email that contains the words easy and money,
有一封包含单词“easy”和“money”的电子邮件
and we want to know if it is spam.
我们想知道它是否为垃圾邮件
So we want this, the probability of the email being
我们要计算的是 包含单词“easy”和“money”时
spam given that it contains the words easy and money.
电子邮件为垃圾邮件的概率
We'll start by using a conditional probability rule that we just reviewed to write it as
我们首先将使用刚刚提到的条件概率规则
a product of the probability that the email
写成电子邮件是垃圾邮件时
contains the words easy and money given that it is spam,
包含单词“easy”和“money”的概率乘以
times the probability of the email being spam.
电子邮件是垃圾邮件的概率
In this formula, A represents being
在此公式中
spam and B represents containing the words easy and money.
A 表示垃圾邮件 B 表示包含单词“easy”和“money”
Now, we are ready to use our naive assumption.
现在可以使用朴素假设了
This first factor over here is a probability of the email
第一个因子是邮件是垃圾邮件时
containing the words easy and money given that it is spam.
包含单词“easy”和“money”的概率
We can write it as a probability of
可以写成邮件是垃圾邮件时
the email containing the word easy given that it is spam,
包含包含单词“easy”的概率乘以
times the probability of the email containing the word money given that it is spam.
邮件是垃圾邮件时包含单词“money”的概率
Again, huge naive assumptions as these may be dependent.
同样是很天真的假设 因为这些项可能相互依赖
It could be that containing the word easy actually makes it more likely that
可能包含单词“easy”后更有可能
the email contains the word money. But that's okay.
包含单词“money” 不过也没关系
In many cases, this assumption won't affect
在很多情况下 这种假设不会影响到结果
the results and it will make our calculations much easier.
并且使计算更轻松
And this is the heart of the Naive Bayes algorithm.
这就是朴素贝叶斯算法的核心
And now, we do the same thing for hand emails.
现在我们对非垃圾邮件执行相同的操作
We have both probabilities written as a product of factors.
我们将两个概率都写成因子的积
But what are these factors?
这些因子是什么？
Well, we've calculated them before based on our data.
我们之前根据数据进行了计算
The first one P of containing the word easy given that it is spam,
第一个因子 即邮件为垃圾邮件时包含单词“easy”的概率是 1/3
is one-third since there are three spam emails and one of them contains the word easy.
因为有 3 封垃圾邮件 其中一封包含单词“easy”
For P of containing money given spam,
邮件为垃圾邮件时
that's two-thirds since there are
包含单词“money”的概率为 2/3
three spam emails and two of them contain the word money.
因为有 3 封垃圾邮件 其中两封包含单词“money”
And P of spam is very simple.
垃圾邮件的概率很简单 为 3/8
It's three over eight since there are eight emails and only three of them are spam.
因为有 8 封电子邮件 只有 3 封是垃圾邮件
We do a similar calculation for the bottom one and get one-fifth,
对底下的进行类似的计算
one-fifth, and five over eight.
结果分别为 1/5 1/5 5/8
Now we multiply them and we get that the probability of spam given
将它们相乘 得出包含单词“easy”和“money”时
that it contains the word easy and money is proportional to one over 12.
邮件为垃圾邮件的概率与 1/12 成比例
And for ham, it's proportional to one over 40.
对于非垃圾邮件 与 1/40 成比例
Now remember that these values are not the actual probabilities,
注意 这些值不是实际概率
they are proportional to the actual probabilities.
它们与实际概率成比例
So what do we do to get the actual probabilities? Here's the magic.
那么如何获取实际概率呢？介绍个神奇的技巧
We know that an email has to be either spam or ham,
我们知道电子邮件要么是垃圾邮件 要么是非垃圾邮件
so these two should add to one.
这两个应该加起来为 1
So we need to normalize them, namely,
我们需要标准化它们
multiply them both by the same factor so that they are still
即乘以相同的因子
proportional to one over 12 and one over 40, but they add to one.
依然与 1/12 和 1/40 成比例 但是加起来是 1
Let's try that in a quiz. Can you find two numbers that add to one and that they are
现在来做一道练习 什么样的两个数字加起来为 1
in the same proportion to each other as one over 12 and one over 40?
并且与 1/12 和 1/40 成相同的比例？
Enter your answer below.
请将你的答案写在下面